Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/manoj-adk (LinkedIn) manojadhikary.com.np/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language) SQL MongoDB

Languages

Nepali, English

Certifications

Working with the Class System in Python

Introduction to Power BI

Getting Started with Data Analytics on AWS

Getting Started with Azure DevOps Boards

Microsoft Certified: Data Analyst Associate

Manoj Adhikari

Microsoft Certified Data Analyst | Python | Django REST API Developer | Data Engineer

Kathmandu

Summary

Experienced Moderator with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Python, Machine Learning, Flask and Django REST API services, WordPress, SQL, MongoDB, Data Analytics, Data modeling and Engineering and Business Intelligence. Strong media and communication professional with a Bachelors focused in Computer Science And Information Technology from St Xavier's College, Maitighar -Kathmandu.

Experience

Renegade Insurance
Data Analyst
March 2022 - Present (5 months)
Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Building top notch Insurance Product - Renegade Insurance (https://renegadeinsurance.com/)

- Product schema engineering
- Data cluster management
- API development
- Automation

BitsKraft (DigiConnect)
Python Developer/ Associate Data Analyst
January 2021 - February 2022 (1 year 2 months)
Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

As a Data Analyst:

- Data Modeling
- Data Transformation
- Data Analysis & Reporting
- Documentation & Communication with related Stakeholders

As a Backend Developer:

- Logics & API development
- Data ETL process development
- Email tracking
- Dark web data leak & exploit search
- Event based process scheduling
- Multi-Factor authentication implementation
- Authenticator Application based authentication
- Roles & permission based access level authorization implementation

Eydean Inc.

Associate Python Developer August 2020 - November 2020 (4 months) Kathmandu

Backend Development, Artificial Intelligence.

St. Xavier's College, Maitighar Research Fellowship October 2018 - September 2019 (1 year) Kathmandu

Fr. Lockie & Stiller Research Awardee 2019

Google Developers Group

Mentor

November 2018 - November 2018 (1 month)

Dang

Mentored SL in ML to more than 50 attendees in Devfest -2018 organized by GDG Dang

Microsoft Innovation Center Nepal hosted by Unlimited Web Design & Content management December 2017 - March 2018 (4 months) kathmandu, Nepal

Trinity Sci-Tech Guild Moderator June 2015 - May 2016 (1 year)

Education

St. Xavier's College, Maitighar

Bachelors, Computer Science And Information Tehnology · (2016 - 2020)

Trinity International College, Dilibazar-Kathmandu Highschool degree, science (physics major) · (2014 - 2016)